(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T21:17:48.240012",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
つまらないデイズ もう散々ね！
Boring days are already so terrible!
奇蹟願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles,
watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets,
i wanna be free! だってまだ振りだし
I wanna be free! Because I'm still at the starting line,
(the party ain’t started)
(The party ain't started)
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙経由
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit,
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のよう
The second hand, like a monster, ticks loudly, urging the night,
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is a magic that melts away in an instant,
それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
If that's the case, then run through it as you wish!
お召しな馬車飛び乗って drivin’
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin',
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我が儘のまにまに爛れに注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness,
洒落た街で dancin’
Dancing in a stylish city.
さようならグッバイ劣等感
Goodbye, inferiority complex,
何時かは喝采クラップオーデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience—
皆々御参和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way,
ガラスシューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight.
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight,
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
So, those who dance freely win, right?
ひとを記憶でひとだと信じ込んで
Believing people are people just by memories,
真の姿がみんなと違うことは
That my true form is different from everyone else—
喧嘩をして
having a fight is fine, right?
構わないよストップじゃない
It's not a stop!
彷徨わずにっちゃえば
If you wander around without hesitation,
ノーストップエンライトやストップじゃない
Non-stop enlighten, or is it a stop?
彷徨わずにっちゃえば
If you wander around without hesitation,
ノーストップエンライトやストップじゃない
Non-stop enlighten, or is it a stop?
探してた明日が 今ここにあるよ
Looking for tomorrow, it's right here now.
追っかけてた昨日を 塗り替えながら
Repainting yesterday as I chased after it.
二度とは戻らない 今日だっていいよ
Even if today never returns, that's fine.
描いてた未来の地図も 生まれ変わるさ
Even the map of the future I drew is reborn.
大丈夫 ずっと この歌を歌いながら
It's alright, always singing this song.
大丈夫 ずっと この歌とここまで来たよ
It's alright, I've come this far with this song.
あの日見上げた星空より高く
Higher than the starry sky I looked up at that day,
夢で想うより遥か遠く
farther than I could ever dream.
今夜連れて行くよ ごらん 星屑の街へ
Tonight I'll take you, look, to the city of stardust.
この夜を越えたら また何処へ行こう
When we cross this night, where shall we go next?
光も時も追い越して巡り逢うから
Outrunning light and time, we'll meet again.
大丈夫 きっと この歌がいつの日にも
It's alright, surely, this song, no matter what day...
大丈夫 きっと この歌は街のどこかで
It's alright, surely, this song, somewhere in the city...
あの日見上げた星空より高く
Higher than the starry sky I looked up at that day,
いつか眠り行く更に遠く
farther still than where we'll someday sleep.
誰も独りじゃない ごらん 星屑の街へ
Nobody is alone, look, to the city of stardust.
あの日見上げた星空より高く
Higher than the starry sky I looked up at that day,
君が想うより遥か遠く
farther than you could ever imagine.
今夜連れて行くよ ごらん 星屑の街へ
Tonight I'll take you, look, to the city of stardust.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
皆さん 本日は 星街すいせい 4周年ライブにお越しいただき 誠にありがとうございます
Everyone, thank you very much for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei's 4th Anniversary Live today.
えー 星街すいせい 4周年ライブで ぜひハッシュタグをつけてツイートしてください
Um, please tweet with the hashtag for Hoshimachi Suisei's 4th Anniversary Live.
それでは 本日はたくさん歌ってまいりますので 次のステージへ そして次の衣装へ 着替えたいと思います
Well then, since we'll be singing a lot today, I'd like to change to the next stage and the next outfit.
うんとこしょっと じゃ
Heave-ho. Well then...
ララライ ララライ
Lala lai, lalalai
誰も知らない 名も無い今を 駆け抜けてくの あの三日月へ 手を伸ばして
Running through an unknown, nameless present, reaching out to that crescent moon.
ララライ ララライ
Lala lai, lalalai
君を知りたい 声にならない 臆病な朝を 例え何度迎えようとも
I want to know you, no matter how many cowardly mornings without a voice we face.
瑕の緒がパチンと切られたその瞬間
The moment the cord of scars snaps cleanly,
世界と逸れてしまったみたいだ
it feels like we've strayed away from the world.
眼に映る景色が悲しく笑うなら 恐れず瞼を閉じて御覧
If the scenery reflecting in your eyes smiles sadly, close your eyes without fear and behold.
さあ！
Now!
皆さん こちらへ
Everyone, over here,
どうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へ
please come where the heartbeat sounds.
さあ！
Now!
躓きを鳴らし どうぞ 心の躍る方へ
Ring your stumbles, please go where your heart dances.
さあ！
Now!
気球楼に飛び乗って さかしまな 世界 乗り熟して
Jump aboard the airship and master the upside-down world.
ララライ ララライ
Lala lai, lalalai
止まらない 愛を知りたいと
Unstoppable, wanting to know love,
願う御呪い 時を超えて
a wishing spell transcending time
朝から夜まで
from morning till night.
ララライ ララライ
Lala lai, lalalai
君を知りたい 何一つ見逃さぬように
I want to know you, so I miss nothing at all.
時は誰も待ってくれるないの
Time won't wait for anyone.
残酷な運命が 抗えぬ宿命が
Cruel destiny, inescapable fate,
考える間もなく 押し寄せ砂塵で
without even time to think, rushing in with a dust storm,
前が見えなくなったって 君を信じてみたいの
even if I can't see ahead, I want to try believing in you.
恐れずに行き歩き出したら
If we step forward without fear...
眠りの手 閉じ込められていた熱が
Heat tightly entrapped, within these sleeping fingers
水際に漂った その色
And becomes the color hanging by the water's border
行き先を忘れて 日々に溶けた
Days melting as they came to forget where they planned to go,
無数の粒が
these countless seeds...
眠りの手 閉じ込められていた熱が
Heat tightly entrapped, within these sleeping fingers
水際に漂った その色
And becomes the color hanging by the water's border
行き先を忘れて 日々に溶けた
Days melting as they came to forget where they planned to go,
無数の粒が
these countless seeds...
夜露 受け入れる器
Dewdrops in early morning, the vessel taking them in
欠けたひとつを 探して
Searching for the one missing piece
夕立ちが名付けられた世界を剥がしたとき
Evening rain falls down on a world given its name and strips it all away,
それは波の様に 指の間をすり抜けて 消えて
it looks just like a tidal wave slipping through fingers and fading away,
形を変え繰り返し 夢だけがわたしを繋いでいる
and only dreams that change form keep connecting me.
君を死にたいくらいに愛せない臆病なあとを
And timidly, unable to love you even unto death,
遠回り 何処へ行こうと
taking the long way around, wherever I might go...
染められない染めないって現実なんてさ
Reality won't let me dye it, won't let me stain it,
目を覆ったってもない
even when covering my eyes, there's nothing left.
暇をかけてゆくの
As time goes on...
あの見果てぬ先で 誰も待ってくれないの
At that far-off end, nobody will wait for me.
鏡面の波
[Title: Kyoumen no Nami]
夜の中をさまよっている 移ろう季節の忘れ物
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night, something forgotten along with the changing seasons
誰かを想う言葉は 誰かの想いに気付けないまま
Words spoken in thought for someone remain unnoticed within another's feelings
澄み切る 鏡の様に澄み込む水面の
As calm as a pristine mirror that you can see right through,
完璧な均衡 永遠の半ば 突き刺す漣 揺らめく
the water's surface is in total harmony, pierced by waves and rippling forevermore
夜の中をさまよっている
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night,
移ろう季節の忘れ物
something forgotten along with changing seasons.
夜の中をさまよっている
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night,
欠けたひとつを探している
searching for that something, a piece they are missing.
舞い上がる風がわたしたちの声を拾ったとき
The wind carries away my voice to places far as it dances playfully,
少しでも迷わない様に 歌に変えていく
and so that it may never be lost, it turns into a lovely song.
夕立ちが名付けられた世界を剥がしたとき
Evening rain falls down on a world given its name and strips it all away,
それは波の様に 指の間をすり抜けて 消えて
it looks just like a tidal wave slipping through fingers and fading away,
形を変え繰り返し
and changing its form over and over,
夢だけがわたしを繋いでいる
dreams alone are connecting me.
夜の中をさまよっている
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night,
夜の中をさまよっている 移ろう季節の忘れ物
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night, something forgotten along with changing seasons...
移ろう季節の 忘れ物を
The changing seasons, leaving behind forgotten things...
誰かを想う 言葉は
Words thought of someone...
誰かの想いに 気付けないまま
Unnoticed in someone else's feelings...
鏡のような 水面に
On a water surface like a mirror...
映る 鏡のような 水面に
Reflected on a water surface like a mirror...
抱く 水面に
Embracing the water surface...
突き刺す 雫 揺らめく
Piercing drops rippling...
夜の中をさまよっている
Wandering aimlessly in the dead of the night...
移ろう季節の忘れ物を
Something forgotten along with changing seasons...
夜の中をさまよっている かけたひとつをさがしている
Wandering aimlessly, searching for that missing piece...
舞い上がる風がわたしたちの声を拾ったとき 少しでも迷わない様に 歌に変えていく
The wind carries away my voice, turning into a song so it won't be lost...
夕立ちが名付けられた世界を剥がしたとき
When evening rain strips away the named world...
夏切られた世界を剥がしたとき
Stripping away the summer world...
それは波のように
It is just like waves...
指の隙間をすり抜けて 消えてしまう
Slipping through the gaps of fingers and fading away...
現れる黒い空
A black sky appears,
鼓動は雷鳴を繰り返す
heartbeats repeat the thunder.
嵐が来る前に
Before the storm arrives,
今宵はあの歌を授けましょう
tonight, let us bestow that song.
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
蘇らせるのさ 愛する君の心
Reviving the heart of the one you love,
身体を脱ぎ捨てて 今我に帰る時
casting off the body, now is the time to return to me.
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
目を眩んで
Blind your eyes,
風を救って
save the wind,
身を溶かして
melt your body,
鐘を鳴らして
ring the bell.
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
雷鳴は何度も産声を上げる
Thunder gives birth to cries time and again.
歌うのさ 闇を越えて飛び出せ
Sing! Leap out beyond the darkness!
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
マハリ ユワレ ガアイェ サバナレ
Mahali yuware gaaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ ガアシャラ
amale dirahi jumagi gaashala
ローリスクじゃ物足りなくなっちゃったし
Low risk is not enough,
有り余って笑っちゃうくらい
laughing because there's too much.
なんてないなんて言ったってしょうがないし
It's no use saying there's nothing,
お手上げでHi-Five
throwing hands up, high five.
前ならえで後に続いたってつまんねえ
Following the front is boring.
夢を語れ、追え！がこの街のStandard
Talking about dreams and chasing are the city's standard.
ただ見ていたいだけなんてのは嘘です
Just wanting to watch is a lie.
そろそろマイク頂戴
Give me the mic soon.
どうせならもう後戻りもできないくらい
Might as well make it impossible to turn back,
なんか、まるで恋してるみたい
feels like I'm in love.
好きになっちゃったぁってつってさ
Saying I've fallen for you,
ならこのまま キミを連れて
so let's go on like this with you,
望むなら どこまででも
wherever you wish.
欲しがってばかりで結構 結構
I just wanna keep wanting, it's fine.
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
ちょっとだけなら無茶だってしちゃいたいし
I want to be a little reckless,
この世の全て奪い尽いちゃうくらい
taking everything in this world.
とはいえ語ってばっかりじゃどうしようもないし
But just talking won't do anything,
語尾跳ねてHi-Fi
jumping high, high five.
ねえ少しはこっち向いたらどう
Hey, what if you look this way a little?
気まぐれにハマらせたいだけ？
Just want to get you hooked on a whim?
でも奪いたい 震わせたい 目、耳、キミの燃えるheart
I want to make you shake, your eyes, ears, and burning heart.
誰をもが羨む驚きのTrackとLyricで
With a track and lyrics that everyone envies,
魅せていくからRetakeはしないで
I'll show you, so don't retake.
だからこのまま キミを連れて 望むなら どこへでも
So let's go on like this with you, anywhere.
欲しがってばかりで結構 結構
I just wanna keep wanting, it's fine.
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
早く夜も明けろ 朝焼けに誓え
Hurry up, night turns into day, promise in the morning glow.
重い想い、熱量を叫べ
Shout out your passion as you please.
この声を聴け 音・音・音に、踊り狂え
Listen to this voice, to the sound, dance wildly.
I want more.
“Are you ready？”
Are you ready?
Ready Steady
ちょっとだけなら無茶だってしちゃいたいし
I want to be a little reckless,
この世の全て奪い尽いちゃうくらい
taking everything in this world.
とはいえ語ってばっかりじゃどうしようもないし
But just talking won't do anything,
語尾跳ねてHi-Fi
jumping high, high five.
ねえ少しはこっち向いたらどう
Hey, what if you look this way a little?
気まぐれにハマらせたいだけ？
Just want to get you hooked on a whim?
でも奪いたい 震わせたい 目、耳、キミの燃えるheart
I want to make you shake, your eyes, ears, and burning heart.
誰をもが羨む驚きのTrackとLyricで
With a track and lyrics that everyone envies,
魅せていくからRetakeはしないで
I'll show you, so don't retake.
だからこのまま キミを連れて 望むなら どこへでも
So let's go on like this with you, anywhere.
欲しがってばかりで結構 結構
I just wanna keep wanting, it's fine.
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
早く夜も明けろ 朝焼けに誓え
Hurry up, night turns into day, promise in the morning glow.
重い想い、熱量を叫べ
Shout out your passion as you please.
この声を聴け 音・音・音に、踊り狂え
Listen to this voice, to the sound, dance wildly.
I want more.
“Are you ready？”
Are you ready?
だからこのまま キミを連れて 望むなら どこへでも
So let's go on like this with you, anywhere.
ないものねだるなら 結構 結構
If you want what you don't have, it's fine.
早く夜も明けろ 朝焼けに誓え
Hurry up, night turns into day, promise in the morning glow.
夏の叫びを
Shout of summer.
この声を聴け 兄弟、とびっきり踊り狂え
Listen to this voice, my brothers, dance wildly.
I want more.
夏の叫びを
Shout of summer.
この声を聴け 兄弟、とびっきり踊り狂え
Listen to this voice, my brothers, dance wildly.
I want more.
Are you ready?
“Are you ready？”
だからこのまま キミを連れて 望むなら どこへでも
So let's go on like this with you, anywhere.
欲しがってばかりで結構 結構
I just wanna keep wanting, it's fine.
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
欲しがってばかりで結構 結構
I just wanna keep wanting, it's fine.
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
もし叶うならこの先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
If it comes true, I want to know and go to the world ahead.
この先の世界を知りたい 行きたい
I want to know and go to the world ahead.
Ready Steady
はーい！ハーイハーイ、ハローエブリワン！ハローエブリーワン、たのし、たのし、かりおぺ、ほんとにうれし！
Hi! Hi hi, hello everyone! Hello everyone, so fun, so fun, Calliope, I'm so happy!
よかった！やったうれしい！わあめちゃ嬉しいほんとに！
Yay! We did it, I'm so happy! Wow, I'm really so happy!
おめでとう、3D！ありがとうございます！こちらこそなんかえっと
Congratulations on 3D! Thank you so much! Same here, like, um...
四周年記念と、誕生日すごい！おめでとうございます！
4th anniversary and birthday, wow! Congratulations!
やった！ありがとうございます！めっちゃんこワクワクしてる、ほんとにね！
Yay! Thank you so much! We're super excited, really!
ワクワクワクワクしてる！やったね！かりおぺの動きがもうなんかもうパワフル、ほんとに！
Super super excited! Yay! Calliope's movements are just so powerful, really!
そうね！いえい！すごい！
That's right! Yay! Amazing!
え、あの、スウィーレルのNumber two、スウィーレルのやつとかはすごい！やった！ほんとにありがとうございます！
Um, Swierl's Number two, Swierl's stuff and all was amazing! Yay! Thank you so much!
なんか今日、あのかりおぺを呼びたいと思ってお呼びさせていただきまして、もうね、過密なスケジュールのなか来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Today, I wanted to invite Calliope and asked her to come, and she came despite her super busy schedule! Thank you so much!
なんかあの、すごい光栄ですよね。ずっと一緒に3Dで歌えたかったから、めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！
It's such an honor. I've always wanted to sing together in 3D, so I'm super happy!
私も嬉しいです！やった！二人すごいね、服とか...
I'm happy too! Yay! You two are amazing, your outfits...
髪とかがすごい
Your hair is amazing!
そうだね
Yeah.
ぴったりね
It's a great match.
ね、私ホワイト、あなたブラック
Hey, I'm white, you're black.
いいね！最高マジで！
Nice! Seriously the best!
最高！イェー！チェックアウト、みんな！
The best! Yeah! Check it out, everyone!
めっちゃ楽しかった
It was so much fun.
楽しかった！よかった、もうレディステディね
It was so fun! I'm glad, "Ready Steady," right?
これを絶対にレコーディングして歌いたいと思って
We wanted to record and sing this for sure.
そうね、ラップの部分いっぱい練習してたし
That's right, we practiced the rap part a lot.
ありがとー！
Thank you!
いや難しいじゃん、日本語のラップ！でもね、もう見事にやってくれましたよ
Japanese rap is hard! But you did an amazing job.
ありがとうございます！本当に頑張りました
Thank you very much! I worked really hard.
えー！皆いかがでしたか？ちょっとコメント読んでいきましょう
Everyone, how was it? Let's read some comments.
いいね、的になってるね！あ、ありがと！ハロー！
Nice, it's hitting the mark! Ah, thanks! Hello!
ハロー！エビバディ！
Hello! Everybody!
ハローハロー、サンキュー！え、プリキュアの涙だって、やった！
Hello hello, thank you! "PreCure tears", yay!
確かに！ブラックとホワイトや
True! Black and white, huh.
そうね、ありがとー！
That's right, thank you!
ラップよかったって！日本語上手だって！え、マジか
They said the rap was great! Japanese is good!
信じられないけど、本当に嬉しいです、マジで！
I can't believe it, I'm really happy, seriously!
ありがと
Thank you.
次、次曲はね、めちゃめちゃ特別な曲です。
Next, the next song is a super special song.
めちゃめちゃスペシャルな曲です！
A super special song!
あ、ニューソング！新曲！
Ah, new song! A new song!
そう、み、あんど、すいすい先輩！
That's right, me and Suisei-senpai!
新曲！新曲！新曲！
New song! New song! New song!
二人のデュエットの新曲が出ますよ！
Our duet new song is coming out!
レッツドゥーイット！
Let's do it!
ということでね、これから歌って回りたいと思いますんで皆さん
So, we're going to sing it around, everyone...
ちょ緊張するな、初披露
I'm a bit nervous, first performance.
そうね、私もめっちゃ緊張してるけど、まあ頑張りましょうね！
I'm super nervous too, but let's do our best!
頑張りましょう！レッツドゥーイット！それでは聞いてください！
Let's do our best! Let's do it! Listen up!
uh uh… suisei! calliope!
Uh-oh... Suisei! Calliope!
鳴呼 もう 何処にしようもないや アウトロー oh oh マリア
Nowhere left to go, an outlaw, oh oh, Maria
high & low 世界を獲りたいな 勝ち取れ 今宵 栄光のcrown
High & low, want the world, win tonight, crown of glory
yea あー ぶっちぎれ 内心 本当は
Yea, ah, break away, deep down inside
説教とか 勘弁ですわ 明日ってんだよ うるさいな
Spare me the lectures, it's tomorrow, how annoying
「それって 常識 ですよ」とか 馬鹿馬鹿しいな
"That's common sense," how absurd
前代未聞 な モン 作ってんだってば
We're making something unprecedented
bring you to heaven road to be wicked
we just gotta break it 植え付けられている情報 レベル
We just gotta break it, planted information's level
疑え 今
Doubt it now
weh-oh-eh-oh 自身の正当性と 戦う の
Weh-oh-eh-oh, fighting our own righteousness
we ain't gonna fake it nobody can trick me
君と 未来 の ため 見つけてくんだよ
For you and the future, we'll keep finding it
a shining shining star
届きそうだ don't try to take it from me
Almost reaching it, don't try to take it from me
right now. this a world where ya get what ' cha give
Right now, this's a world where ya get whatcha give
and i 'm a girl of a whole lotta adjectives
And I'm a girl of a whole lotta adjectives
a couple might say “ stubborn , rude , hard to please ”
A couple might say "stubborn, rude, hard to please"
and the crazys appraise me wit “ secret sleaze ”
And the crazys appraise me wit "secret sleaze"
now guys , please .
Now guys, please.
i gave first to get a lot
now i 'm spittin ' here with suisei , burning hot
Now I'm spittin' here with Suisei, burning hot
shining star
's bizarre
It's bizarre
can't ya see the scars ?
Can't ya see the scars?
we hit the grind , now we shine , look how goddamn far
We hit the grind, now we shine, look how goddamn far
we done came
a shame it 's a numbers game
A shame it's a numbers game
to some
fun first , fame second
Fun first, fame second
we ain't dumb .
We ain't dumb.
because we
livin ' in the moment and we own it , okay ? we done ?
Livin' in the moment and we own it, okay? We done?
paving our way , for one
Paving our way, for one
aim to outshine the sun
taming a loaded gun ?
Taming a loaded gun?
give it a try .
Give it a try.
ya better pick a direction and run .
Ya better pick a direction and run.
without an alibi
you can't deny
that maybe you been sleep in '\
That maybe you been sleepin'
come on get a grip , here 's a tip , don't stop dream in ' .
Come on get a grip, here's a tip, don't stop dreamin'.
road to be wicked
we just gotta break it
植え付けられている情報 レベル 疑え 今
Planted information's level, doubt it now
weh-oh-eh-oh 自身の正当性と 戦う の
Weh-oh-eh-oh, fighting our own righteousness
とても不思議ね
It's so mysterious
君といるときだけ
Only when I'm with you
他の誰も知らない 私見せたり
Showing a side no one else knows
時が止めればとか考えていたり
Or wondering if time would just stop
恋焦がれた夢の場所へ来たのよ long long way
I've come to the long-yearned dream place, long long way
road to be wicked
we just gotta break it
上見れば次のレベル 近づいたら
Looking up to the next level, as we get closer
weh-oh-eh-oh 自身のモノサシで 続けるの
Weh-oh-eh-oh, keeping on with our own measure
知る度熟れて 優しいさをえ
Maturing as we know more, gaining kindness
それぞれの幸せ 皆わかっていくんだよ
Everyone comes to understand their own happiness
just moving moving on そんな 運命だ
Just moving moving on, such is our destiny
born to be wicked , and we aim to fly
Born to be wicked, and we aim to fly
whether angels , or devils , it is do or die
Whether angels, or devils, it is do or die
no cap , kick it while the sound is hot
No cap, kick it while the sound is hot
we broke backs just to get what we got
ah . . ay . .
Ah... ay...
born to be wicked and we aim to fly
cuz we still ain't found that eternal sky
ya know ?
Ya know?
そう 産まれすんだよ
That's how we were born
i 'll find a way out we movin movin on ya
I'll find a way out, we movin movin on ya
季節は次々死んでいく
The seasons die off one by one
絶命の声が風になる
The voices of demise turn to winds
色めく街の 酔えない男
The man who can't get drunk, of this colorful town
月を見上げるのはここじゃ無粋
It's unromantic to look up at the moon here
泥に足もつれる生活に
In the life where my legs get trapped by the mud,
雨はアルコールの味がした
the rain tasted of alcohol
アパシーな目で 彷徨う街で
With an apathetic eye, in the town he wanders
挙動不審のイノセント
Suspiciously innocent,
駅前にて ぼくがぼくを呼ぶには不確かだな
in front of the station, it's uncertain for me to call myself me
半透明な影が生きている風だ
It's like a translucent shadow is living
雨に歌えば 雲は割れるか
If I sing to the rain, would the clouds break?
賑やかな夏の 干涸びた命だ
It's a withered life, in a boisterous summer
拝啓 忌まわしき過去に告げる 絶縁の詩
Salutations to the loathsome past, a break-up verse
最低な日々の 最悪な夢の
The relics of the worst days and worst dreams
残骸を捨てては行けず
cannot be left behind and thrown away,
ここで息絶えようと
so I'll just die right here.
後世 花は咲き君に伝える 変遷の詩
After ages, flowers bloom and convey the verse of transition
苦悩にまみれて 嘆き悲しみ
Smeared in agony, grieving and lamenting sadness,
それでも途絶えぬ歌に 陽は射さずとも
and yet, the song never ends, even without the sun
明日は次々死んでいく
Tomorrows die off one by one,
急いでも追い付けず過去になる
even if we hurry, it becomes the past
生き急げ僕ら 灯る火はせつな
We rush to live, the fire is lit for a moment
生きる意味などは後からつく
A reason to live comes later
君が君でいるには不確かだな
An unstable ego makes it uncertain for you to be yourself
不安な自我が君を嫌おうと
even if it hates you
せめて歌えば 闇は晴れるか
At least, if I sing, would the darkness clear?
根腐れた夢に預かった命だ
A life placed in my hands from a root-rotten dream
拝啓 忌まわしき過去に告げる 絶縁の詩
Salutations to the loathsome past, a break-up verse
最低な日々の 最悪な夢の 残骸を
Relics of the worst days and worst dreams
捨てては行けず ここで息絶えようと
cannot be thrown away, trying to die right here
後世 花は咲き君に伝える 変遷の詩
After ages, flowers bloom and convey the verse of transition
苦悩にまみれて 嘆き悲しみ
Smeared in agony, grieving and lamenting sadness,
それでも途絶えぬ歌に 陽は射さずとも
and yet, the song never ends, even without the sun
疲れた顔に足を引きずって
Dragging my legs with a tired face,
照らし返す夕日に顔をしかめて
frowning at the reflecting sunset
行こうか戻ろうか 悩みはするけど
Should I go? Should I return? I wonder, but
しばらくすれば 歩き出す背中
after some time, I start walking
そうだ行かねばならない 何はなくとも生きていくのだ
Yes, I must go and live on no matter what
僕らはどうせ拾った命だ
Our lives are what we picked up anyway
ここに置いてくよ なけなしの
I'll leave what's little of it here
拝啓 今は亡き過去を想う 望郷の詩
Salutations to the past, a verse of nostalgia
チュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュル
Chururu...
水際引いては満ちて
Where the water's edge ebbs and flows,
胸騒ぎ
a premonition stirs.
もうきっと潮時よ
It must be time to go.
顔と名前の貸借
Borrowing faces and names,
足を洗うべきよ
I should wash my hands of it.
媚びと恨みの売買
Trading flattery and grudges,
泥生の街で
In this muddy town.
輪廻の輪に還る命
Lives returning to the wheel of samsara,
雲にまみれて 嘆き悲しみ
Covered in clouds, weeping and mourning,
それでも途絶えぬ歌に
Yet in a song that never fades,
火は差さずとも
Even if no fire shines,
命は朽ちずとも
Even if life does not decay...
絶望 つぎつぎ つぎ替える
Despair, replacing one after another.
チュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュル
Chururu...
もうきっと潮時よ
It must be time to go.
顔と名前の貸借 足を洗うべきよ
Borrowing faces and names, I should wash my hands of it.
媚びと恨みの売買 泥生の街で
Trading flattery and grudges in this muddy town.
真相は 泥生の街で
The truth in this muddy town...
同じさ 語るまじ
It's the same, best not to speak of it.
世の煩い 当然の報いだよ
The troubles of the world are only natural retribution.
仇と利息の返済
Repayment of grudges and interest,
手を染めた罰よ おんと喧嘩の売買
The punishment for dirtying my hands, trading favors and fights.
裏切りの 衝動は
The impulse of betrayal,
秋の夜の 恋煩い
Lovesickness on an autumn night.
浮かれるか沈むか
Whether to float or sink,
暗黙のTokyo Harbour
In the silent Tokyo Harbour.
頭から生破裂して舞う ああ青息吐息
Bursting from the head and dancing, ah, sighing in distress.
笑顔が眩しいね 見納め小雨
Smiles are dazzling, a parting drizzle,
頬を叩く茶泡を振らす
Stirring up foam striking my cheeks.
大博打思惑師 赤プリがもぬけならば
A high-stakes gambler, if Akasaka Prince is vacant,
終わりゆく時代へ Age kiss
To an ending era, age kiss.
毎度あり通り あの八番出口も用なしね
Business as usual, that Exit 8 is no longer needed either.
笑顔が眩しいね
Smiles are dazzling,
見納め小雨
a parting drizzle.
頬を叩く茶泡を振らす
Stirring up foam striking my cheeks.
泡僕じゃ泡を拭かす
Making foam rise...
口紅を模し
Imitating lipstick,
赤く光りかも抜け並べ並ばぬばかりの気負い冗談
Glowing red...
終わりゆく時代へ
To an ending era,
毎度あり通り
Business as usual,
あの八番出口も用なしね ため息三山
That Exit 8 is no longer needed either, a sigh over Sannou.
水際引いては満ちて
Where the water's edge ebbs and flows,
胸騒ぎ もうきっと潮時よ
a premonition stirs, it must be time to go.
チュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュル
Chururu...
チュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュルチュル 騒ぎ
Chururu... commotion.
腐抜け出した心に i need you
In my spineless heart, I need you.
噂のアルカロイド
The rumored alkaloid.
あだ名はネットの顱骨 かき鳴らせディストーション
My nickname is a net's skull, strum the distortion.
付け焼き刃の侍が
A makeshift samurai...
拗らせ心に i need you
In a foolish heart, I need you,
噂のアルカロイド
the rumored alkaloid.
あだ名はネットの晒し首
Nickname is the internet's target of ridicule,
鳴らし響かせディストーション
resound the distortion.
付け焼き刃の侍が乱れ打つ散弾銃
The makeshift samurai fires shotgun shells in a frenzy.
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか
Shall we dance in the history of tragedy?
ほら てんてこ へんてこ まいまい はあ
Look, it's all topsy-turvy, crazy, ha!
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度
My heart is an ego rock at a 45-degree angle,
ナンセンス
pure nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いて
Crush the know-how,
マネネリを明日にバイバイバイバイ
say bye-bye to tomorrow's routine.
媚び諂うその姿
The flattering, fawning appearance,
吐き気の空模様
a nauseating sky.
シニカルな視線の雨
The rain of cynical glances,
今日も両目を塞ぐふり
today too pretending to close both eyes.
おちゃらけ心に i need you
In a playful heart, I need you,
ちまたのアルカロイド
the town's alkaloid.
あの雲もはやりのインスタントショー
That cloud's already a trendy instant show,
巻き散らせ デッド
scattering the dead.
鬱達が上がらぬ侍が
The frustrated samurai stands for the future,
未来立つ 哀悼歌
a song of lament.
むざんな歴史で歌おうよ
Let's sing of a miserable history,
ほら ちゃんちゃら なんちゃら まいまい はあ
look, it's all ridiculous nonsense, ha!
ロックな心で生きようか 真夏波浪
Let's live with a rock heart, midsummer waves,
ほっとなミュージック
hot music.
はうつくないて 丸括って
Crush the pain, round it up,
明日もははは
tomorrow is also ha ha ha.
しゃらくささも癖になる
Frivolous nature becomes a habit,
はみ出し者だろう
you're a misfit, aren't you?
りりかるな視線の雨
Lyrical rain of glances,
今日も両目を開くふり
today too pretending to open both eyes.
透明な感情は染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions just get stained,
染まるだけさ
just get stained.
だから見てみぬふりをする奴らを押し出せ
So push away those who pretend not to see.
人生かけても負けそうですか
Even if life is at stake, are you about to lose?
勝ち負け取り憑かれナンセンス
Possessed by winning and losing, nonsense.
いっぴん砕いて常識を
Crush common sense for an instant,
未来にセイグッバイ
say goodbye to the future.
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度
My heart is an ego rock at a 45-degree angle,
ナンセンス
pure nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いて
Crush the know-how,
マネネリを明日にバイバイバイバイ
say bye-bye to tomorrow's routine.
媚び諂うその姿
The flattering, fawning appearance,
吐き気の空模様
a nauseating sky.
シニカルな視線の雨
The rain of cynical glances,
今日も両目を塞ぐふり
today too pretending to close both eyes.
シニカルな視線の雨
The rain of cynical glances,
今日も両目を塞ぐふり
today too pretending to close both eyes.
1 2 3
fuck you!
はーい ということでみなさん
Alright, so everyone,
こんにちは わいわい！
hello, yay yay!
えーっと ここまで5曲歌わせていただきました
Um, we've sung five songs so far,
かりよぺとの2曲と えーあ6曲だった最初の一曲と
two songs with Calliope, and um, wait, six songs with the first one,
あ、全然違った。えっと、あ、9曲歌ってました。
Ah, that's totally wrong. Um, ah, I've sung nine songs.
いや、頭がバグってました。みなさんこんにちは。
Man, my brain was glitching. Hello everyone.
えっとですね、いや3連続で、いや4連続か、かりよぺとの、じゃ最後の一曲、え、ヴィケットから4連続で歌わせていただいて
Um, you know, three in a row—no, four in a row, with Calliope... wait, starting from the last song, 'Wicked', I sang four in a row.
えっと、どうでしたか？
Um, how was it?
すいちゃ、記憶が、やばい。
Suichan, my memory is—yikes.
ちょっとね、緊張してるかもしれない、何かが起こるかもしれないと思って、いま緊張で震えてるかもしれない。
I might be a little nervous, thinking something might happen, so I might be shaking with tension right now.
あ、トレンド1位とかもありがとうございます。
Oh, and thank you for trending number one and stuff.
えっと、この衣装
Um, this outfit,
すごいでしょう？
isn't it amazing?
新衣装作ってもらいました！ ぜひさにいぇいい！
They made a new outfit for me! Yay, yay!
いいカメラでの新衣装後ろとかもね。ほら、どうですか？
Look at the back of the new outfit with the good camera. See, how is it?
ホロ初公開の後姿です。
This is Hololive's very first public showing of the back view.
なんか緊張してて、あの新衣装だっていうことも忘れてました。
I was so nervous, I even forgot it was a new outfit.
いや、あるよね。よーしんでおめでとう、ありがとう！
Well, those things happen. Happy early birthday, thank you!
えっと、実はこの衣装なんですけど、ジャケットが、ありますよね。
Um, actually, with this outfit, there's a jacket, right?
ジャケットが ジャケット見たい？
Jacket? Do you want to see the jacket?
ジャケットもあるよ。ジャケット見たいよね？
There's a jacket too. You want to see the jacket, right?
じゃちょっと今からあの、マジックするんで 行きますよ。
Well, I'm going to do some magic right now, so here we go.
じゃカメラさん 行きますよー！
Camera-san, here we go!
ほい！ ほいーのほい！
Hoi! Hoi! Hoi!
え、どうですか？ はいはいはいはいはいはい！
Well, how is it? Yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay!
いかが？ はいはいはい、いかが？
How is it? Yay, yay, yay, how is it?
かわいい？
Is it cute?
かわいい
Cute.
いいね。
Nice.
足から ちょっと見てください。
Take a look from my legs.
はい、足。
Yes, my legs.
これ足ね。
These are my legs, you see.
はいはいはいはいはいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right, right...
はいはいはいはいはいはいはいはいはいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right...
赤い！
Red!
あれこれ、この後ろ、ジャケットのこの後ろのさ、オレンジ、本邦初公開。
This orange on the back of my jacket—first time ever revealed!
はい、はい、はい。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
やったーー！
Yay!
口にあたっちゃったマイクが、笑
My mic hit my mouth, haha.
えー。
Um...
はい、えー運営さんを脅して作らせました。笑
Yeah, I threatened management to make this for me, haha.
可愛い衣装です。
It's a cute outfit.
やった！
Yay!
いや、あの、気づいた方もいるかもしれないんですけど、
Some of you might have noticed,
ちょ今回はね、6兆の曲をたくさん選曲させていただいておりまして。
this time I've chosen a lot of Roku-chou songs.
で、6兆の曲にすごい合う衣装なんじゃないかなと思っております。
And I think this outfit matches those songs really well.
ではね、次の曲行きたいんですけど、まずちょここじゃなくて向こうで歌うんで、ちょ向こうに戻りたいと思います。
I want to move on to the next song, but I'm going to sing over there.
それじゃあ戻りますよ。
Alright, I'm heading back.
今から。
Starting now.
よし。
Alright.
はい、後ろ向いた。
Yep, turned around.
はい、走っていきます。
Alright, I'm running.
おいでよ。
Come along.
みんなーー！みんなーー！すいちゃんだよ、花道を！
Everyone! It's Suichan, walking down the runway!
花道を歩いています、すいちゃん。
Suichan is walking down the runway.
はい。はい、戻ってきたー。
Yep. Yep, I'm back.
はい、戻ってきた。
Yep, I'm back.
ふう。
Phew.
ということでね、このメインステージに戻ってきたということで、
Having returned to this main stage,
えー、そろそろみんなも次の曲聴きたいよね？
everyone's ready to hear the next song, right?
次は何じゃろな？
I wonder what's next?
も気づいたら45分経ってる。
Before I knew it, 45 minutes have passed.
はい。 ではね、行きますよ。 それでは次の曲聴いてください。
Alright, here we go. Please listen to the next song.
かけろ！
Run!
本音も建前も
Both true intentions and facades,
駆け引き上手な大人達は駄目だね
adults who are good at playing games are no good.
そんな言葉 信用できない
I can't trust words like that.
便利で快適で進化し続けるテクノロジー
Technology keeps evolving, convenient and comfortable.
伝えて 人肌のぬくもり
Convey the warmth of human skin.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of ceaseless rain.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm no longer sad; humans are creatures who get used to it.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だっけ
Which page of youth has become a blank sheet again?
今、君に会いたいと 涙こみ上げる
Now, wanting to see you, tears well up.
踏んだり蹴ったり 注意散漫 人生の転機だ
Kicked and stepped on, scattered attention—a turning point in life.
新しい時代を乗りこなしていくんだ
I'm going to ride out this new era.
透明で 不鮮明で 叫び声あげるマイノリティ
Transparent, unclear, shouting minority.
健気に 失敗しては学んでく
Courageously making mistakes and learning.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of ceaseless rain.
愛するしかない それしかできない 器用じゃないから
I have no choice but to love, because I'm clumsy.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だっけ
Which page of youth has become a blank sheet again?
忘れ物思い出せないまま 忘れそう
I might forget without even remembering what I left behind.
風の形見えない 見えないよ あなたが あなただって同じ
I can't see the wind's shape—you're the same, you too.
動き出すよ この身かけて 零さないよ
I'll start moving, putting my all into it, and won't let it spill.
泣いたってしょうがないさ
It's no use crying.
降り止まない 雨の世界だ
It's a world of ceaseless rain.
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm no longer sad; humans are creatures who get used to it.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だっけ
Which page of youth has become a blank sheet again?
今、君に会いたいと涙こらえて
Now, holding back tears wanting to see you,
さよならだ さよならなんだって認めたくないけど
even though I don't want to admit it's a final goodbye.
雨上がりの この世界が眩しいから
Because this world after the rain is so dazzling.
もう帰らない 振り返らない 思い出と共に
I won't return, won't look back, together with my memories.
新しい風に煽られて そしてまた君に会いたいと願い 駆け抜けてゆく
Fanned by a new breeze, wishing once more to see you, I run through.
風の形見えない 見えないよ あなたが
I can't see the wind's shape—you...
あなただって同じ ジッとなんてしてられない動き
You're the same, unable to stay still!
出そうよ この身 かけて行こうさ
Let's put our all into it and go!
ないよ 泣いたってしょうがないさ
There's none—it's no use crying!
ねぇこのままずっと 降り止まない 雨の世界だ
Hey, this ceaseless rainy world forever...
もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm not sad; humans get used to it.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だっけ
Which page of youth became blank?
今 君に会いたいと 涙 こらえてさようならだ
Now, holding back tears wanting to see you, it's goodbye.
さようならなんだって認め たくないけど
Even though I don't want to admit it's goodbye,
雨上がりの この世界が眩しすぎて もう変えらない 振り返らない
this world after rain is too dazzling, I won't change or look back,
思い出とともに 新しい風に 新しい君と…
together with memories, with a new wind, with a new you...
息つく暇もないほど
With no time to even catch my breath,
走り抜けてきた
I've been running through.
今、君に会いたいと願い
Now, I want to see you so badly,
泣きこみあげて
I burst into tears.
かけてゆく
I'm going to keep chasing after you.
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで 作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
[Music]
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light has flickered on...
灯った
It flickered on.
天を彩った靆が綺麗だ
The twilight coloring the heavens is so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように、
If only I could erase it,
消してしまえたらな
just like the white breath I exhale...
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressing it deep down inside,
泣き声さえ、聞こえているから
even your cries can be heard.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も、
The anxiety and pain that pierced you...
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint it all over with my azure blue,
全部涙になって
turning into tears entirely,
星の海を流れていった
flowing through the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に
Into the endless darkness,
そっと青を添えたら、ほら
gently adding blue... Look!
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet soared across the sky above me,
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
dyeing the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ
Deep into the sleeping town,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
whose sorrow is it that falls like rain?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The star flew, tracing an arc once again.
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away the hazy thoughts,
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't bring myself to say,
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ
In the town after the stars fell, I'm still...
黒くくすんだがくらんどうの空を
painting the murky, chaotic sky
彗星が彩るように
as if the stars were adorning it.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も、
The anxiety and pain that pierced you...
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint it all over with my azure blue,
君の涙をそっと、星の海に流し込むんだ
and gently let your tears flow into the sea of stars.
尾を引いたその光が、誰かをまた救うから
Because that light, leaving a trail,
誰もをまた救うから
will save someone once again.
この空を全部君にあげるよ
That's why I'll give all this sky to you.
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away the hazy thoughts,
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't bring myself to say,
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
"We can meet again sometime."
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
The anxiety and pain that pierced you...
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint it all over with my azure blue,
悲しみが溢れそうになること
Even if sadness overflows to the point of breaking,
天球で離ればなれになれても
even if we drift apart into the firmament,
僕らは繋がってるから
we are still connected.
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet soared across the sky above me,
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
dyeing the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ
Deep into the sleeping town,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
whose sorrow is it that falls like rain?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The star flew, tracing an arc once again.
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away the hazy thoughts,
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't bring myself to say,
君の行方を探してた
I've been searching for where you are going.
画面の向こうのそのまた向こうで
Beyond the screen, further than that,
放たれた言葉たち
the words that were set free.
殴っても痛まない透明な拳
Transparent fists that don't hurt even when striking
満天の星のように散らばっている
are scattered like stars across the whole sky.
ガラスの破片の上を裸足で歩くような痛みだ
It's a pain like walking barefoot on shards of glass.
僕はづっと苦しかったんだ
I've been suffering all along.
「正解」なんてどうだっていい
"Right answers" or whatever don't matter at all to me.
この世界が正しいか間違いか
Whether this world is right or wrong,
自分で決めるからその手に抱えた大層なテンプレートを
I'll decide for myself, holding that grand template in my hands.
持ち替えて鏡に映った僕の色は全部
Swapping it out, all the colors of me reflected in the mirror
僕のためにあったのに気づいたらこの手を離れていた
were meant for me, but before I knew it, they slipped from my hands.
名前も顔も隠したアノニマスに僕の何がわかるの？
What could an anonymous person hiding their name and face ever understand about me?
輪郭さえぼやけそうな痛みを僕の全部取り返さなくちゃ
I have to take back all of myself from this pain blurring even my outline.
何度遮ったってうるさいほどになるノイズが
No matter how many times I block it out, the deafening noise grows louder.
好き勝手僕を閉じ込めるカテゴライズの檻に縛ってさ、僕の声の正体
Tied up in the cage of categorization locking me away as it pleases—what is the true identity of my voice?
名前をつけるのは自分だけだろう？
Only I can give it a name, right?
もう僕は祈らない
I won't pray anymore.
この街の頭上を降り注いだ慈愛を僕は信じない
I don't believe in the affection poured down over this city's sky.
僕のこの痛みも姿も誰に決められることもない
Neither this pain nor my form will ever be decided by anyone else.
「正解」なんてどうだっていい
"Right answers" or whatever don't matter at all to me.
この世界が正しいか間違いか自分で決めるから
Whether this world is right or wrong, I'll decide for myself.
あの一等星の輝きにも
Even to the brilliance of that first-magnitude star,
幸福が蔓延る理想郷にも
or to the utopia overflowing with happiness,
届かなくたって構わない
I don't care if I never reach them.
僕以外、何も要らない
I need nothing else, only myself.
星街すいせい New Single「TEMPLATE / Wicked feat. Mori Calliope」
Hoshimachi Suisei's New Single "TEMPLATE / Wicked feat. Mori Calliope"
先輩、すいせいは夜をまたいでを手掛けたキタニタツヤさんに書き下ろしてもらいました！
was written for me by Tatsuya Kitani, who also created "Yoru o Mataide"!
このあと24時から各種音楽配信サービスにて配信開始となります。
It will be available on various music streaming services starting at midnight tonight.
先ほど披露した、はりつけとのデュエット曲「Wicked」もカップリング曲として一緒に配信されますよ。
And "Wicked", the duet song with Calliope performed earlier, will also be released alongside it as a coupling track.
そしてこのあと「TEMPLATE」のMVがすいせいチャンネルで投稿されるので是非チェックしてください。
Also, the music video for "TEMPLATE" will be posted on Suisei's channel right after this, so please check it out!
そして...
And...
あの一等星の輝きにも
Even to the brilliance of that first-magnitude star,
幸福が蔓延る理想郷にも届かなくたって...
or to the utopia overflowing with happiness, even if I never reach them...
さらに、星街すいせい誕生日＆活動4周年記念グッズが発売決定して...
Furthermore, Hoshimachi Suisei's Birthday & 4th Anniversary commemorative goods are now on sale...
記念グッズはアクリルパネル、キャップ、サーモタンブラー、スマホリングの4種類です。
The commemorative goods consist of 4 items: an acrylic panel, a cap, a thermo tumbler, and a smartphone ring.
そしてグッズ4種が1つになった誕生日＆活動4周年記念フルセットも売られますよ。フルセットを購入すると、複製サイン入りポストカードがついてきます！
And the Birthday & 4th Anniversary Full Set, combining all 4 goods, will also be available. Purchasing the full set comes with a replica autographed postcard!
配信後22時から販売開始ですので是非手に入れてください。
Sales begin at 22:00 right after the stream, so please make sure to get yours!
あっ
Ah,
みんなー！
everyone!
いや、どうだった？ライブ。
So, how was the live?
あのー、あれだね。告知がすごくもりだくさんでしたね。
Um, well, there were so many announcements, right?
え、なんと最後にもう一つあります！
And guess what, there's one last thing!
え、何から？何から？まだあるの？
Huh? From what? What, there's more?
じゃあ、えーこの動画を流して今日のライブは終わりといたします。
Well, um, we'll play this video and conclude today's live.
では、動画どうぞっ！
Now, roll the video!
MIDNIGHT GRAND ORCHESTRA
星街すいせい & TAKU INOUE New Music Project『Midnight Grand Orchestra』
[Hoshimachi Suisei & TAKU INOUE New Music Project "Midnight Grand Orchestra"]
To Be Announced 2022.04.06
Selfish of a Rough Stone Hoshimachi Suisei 4th Anniversary
[Hoshimachi Suisei 4th Anniversary Live: "Selfish of a Rough Stone"]